<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Dane Williams</title>
    <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Dane Williams</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:52:09 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Published my first academic research paper</title>
      <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/published-my-first-academic-research-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:52:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/published-my-first-academic-research-paper/</guid>
      <description>During the Fall 2020 and Spring 2021 semesters I have been working on a research project in Professor Chaoli Wang&amp;rsquo;s Visualization Lab here at Notre Dame. My team and I have been studying Sankey diagrams, and how we can better illustrate data flow. Specifically we have been analyzing data from ND Learning, and organization on campus that aims to improve learning experiences at Notre Dame for people of all backgrounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m joining a software startup!</title>
      <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/im-joining-a-software-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 00:52:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/im-joining-a-software-startup/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago, I saw on Linkedin that a fellow vampire, Zeno Rocha had started a new job at a startup called WorkOS. He said the team was looking to bring on more software engineers and developer experience engineers, so I scheduled a call and learned more about the company from him.
I quickly became very impressed by what Zeno had shared with me about the company as well as from the research I had done and began the interview process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My experience interning at Qualtrics</title>
      <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/my-experience-interning-at-qualtrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:52:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/my-experience-interning-at-qualtrics/</guid>
      <description>Over the summer I interned at Qualtrics which is an enterprise SaaS company that pioneered the experience management category. This was a really cool experience as it was essentially the first time I worked in a modern software engineering team environment. I was a part of the PX - Frontline Feedback product team, which is responsible for both building new features for Qualtrics Frontline Feedback, as well as maintaining the product&amp;rsquo;s platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing playruski.com</title>
      <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/introducing-play-ruski/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:52:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/introducing-play-ruski/</guid>
      <description>As a final project for our databases class my friends Jack, Conor, Billy, and I decided to make a web app for a popular sport in our dorm at Notre Dame called Ruski. I won&amp;rsquo;t get into the specifics of the game, but basically we thought it would be interesting to collect data on game results so that we could then rank players.
Games are typically played in a 2v2 format, so we came up with an algorithm that modifies the Elo rating system in order to rank players.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a pastebin and url shortener with serverless AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/pastebin-with-serverless-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:52:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/pastebin-with-serverless-aws/</guid>
      <description>Overview I recently set out to build an application with serverless AWS that would visualize imessage chat data in d3. After some digging and learning more about AWS I figured out that my idea wasn&amp;rsquo;t really viable with the exact vision that I had. Not wanting to let the work I put in go to waste, I pivoted to making a pastebin and url shortener instead. I build it in Python using the Chalice framework, to develop serverless Lambda function, S3 buckets, and API Gateway that make up the backend of the pastebin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited to Google FooBar!</title>
      <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/google-foobar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:52:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/google-foobar/</guid>
      <description>Discovery Recently I was looking up some java documentation as I have not worked with the language since my AP CS class sophomore year of high school, and ended up coming across an exciting surprise!
Intrigued, I proceeded by clicking the button &amp;ldquo;I want to play&amp;rdquo;, and discovered the Google FooBar challenge! Clicking the button led me to a terminal in the browser with some instructions, which allows for your to request different coding challenges which can be solved in python 2 (no python 3 :/ ) or in java.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo tutorial for total beginners</title>
      <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/hugo-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:52:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/hugo-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Hugo Website Tutorial Recently my younger brother who is in high school and is beginning to learn more about programming expressed interest in building his own portfolio site, similar to this one. I figured I would help him out by making a tutorial for complete beginners.
This is an all inclusive tutorial on how to make a static personal site using the Hugo framework. Experience with command line, git, markdown, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an AI chatbot</title>
      <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/building-an-ai-chat-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:52:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/building-an-ai-chat-bot/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the Notre Dame CSE slack we have a bot named bobbit which performs many commands providing a lot of entertainment and functionality. I decided that it could be fun to build my own bot for use in my water polo team groupme so that we could easily get information about tournament schedules, pool time openings, etc. This led me down a rabbit hole of python bots where I eventually discovered ChatterBot, a machine learning conversational dialog engine for chatbots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Having fun with zig lang</title>
      <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/having-fun-with-zig-lang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:52:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/having-fun-with-zig-lang/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Some fellow Notre Dame CS students made the awesome pbui-project, the POSIX-compliant BSD/Linux Userland Implementation, which is a userland implementation written entirely in zig. Out of curiosity for trying out zig I decided to make a small pull request implementing the pwd command.
Thoughts on Zig Since I had next to no background knowledge on zig programming, there was a lot less time coding and a lot more time spent reading documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing an http web server in C</title>
      <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/developing-an-http-web-server-in-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:52:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/developing-an-http-web-server-in-c/</guid>
      <description>Introduction As the final project for my systems programming class at Notre Dame my partner, Conor Murphy, and I developed a simple http web server server (similar to apache). We did this entirely in C, which was a great opportunity to learn about networking specific issues such as commication over sockets, as well as low level functions and system calls for memory allocation and file/directory manipulation.
Development I&amp;rsquo;ll spare the details here but the development process for this was very reading heavy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first open source contribution! (dracula/tmux)</title>
      <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/my-first-open-source-contribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 22:59:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/my-first-open-source-contribution/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Recently I have begun using the awesome dracula theme for most of my development tools. Unfortunately, one of my favorite tools, tmux did not have a dracula theme (until now).
Methodology A couple weeks ago, towards the beginning of corona virus quarantine here in the Bay Area, I decided to take it upon myself to develop a dracula theme extension for tmux while I had a bit of extra time due to Notre Dame going online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial Post</title>
      <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/initial-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:52:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/initial-post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog! I plan to use this site to share my projects and code with the world, and may occasionally speak to other interests of mine. I am currently a CS student at Notre Dame, and you can learn more about me by checking out my about page.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
