<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dane Williams</title>
    <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dane Williams</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:52:09 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.danewilliams.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Having fun with zig lang</title>
      <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/having-fun-with-zig-lang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:52:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/having-fun-with-zig-lang/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Some fellow Notre Dame CS students made the awesome pbui-project, the POSIX-compliant BSD/Linux Userland Implementation, which is a userland implementation written entirely in zig. Out of curiosity for trying out zig I decided to make a small pull request implementing the pwd command.
Thoughts on Zig Since I had next to no background knowledge on zig programming, there was a lot less time coding and a lot more time spent reading documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing an http web server in C</title>
      <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/developing-an-http-web-server-in-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:52:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/developing-an-http-web-server-in-c/</guid>
      <description>Introduction As the final project for my systems programming class at Notre Dame my partner, Conor Murphy, and I developed a simple http web server server (similar to apache). We did this entirely in C, which was a great opportunity to learn about networking specific issues such as commication over sockets, as well as low level functions and system calls for memory allocation and file/directory manipulation.
Development I&amp;rsquo;ll spare the details here but the development process for this was very reading heavy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first open source contribution! (dracula/tmux)</title>
      <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/my-first-open-source-contribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 22:59:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/my-first-open-source-contribution/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Recently I have begun using the awesome dracula theme for most of my development tools. Unfortunately, one of my favorite tools, tmux did not have a dracula theme (until now).
Methodology A couple weeks ago, towards the beginning of corona virus quarantine here in the Bay Area, I decided to take it upon myself to develop a dracula theme extension for tmux while I had a bit of extra time due to Notre Dame going online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial Post</title>
      <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/initial-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:52:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/initial-post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog! I plan to use this site to share my projects and code with the world, and may occasionally speak to other interests of mine. I am currently a CS student at Notre Dame, and you can learn more about me by checking out my about page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danewilliams.me/about/</guid>
      <description>I am an undergraduate computer science student at the University of Notre Dame graduating in 2022. Outside of my studies I spend much of my time at the pool playing for the Notre Dame men&amp;rsquo;s water polo team. Originally, I am from the Bellevue/Eastside area of Seattle, where I attended Eastside Catholic School and graduated in 2018. I am also a proud alumni of the Bellevue Club Swim Team. Since leaving for college my family moved to the Bay Area so that is where I reside while on breaks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danewilliams.me/projects/</guid>
      <description>What I&amp;rsquo;ve Been Working On I will try to update this page as I complete new projects, however the most up to date location of all my projects is of course my github. I also have a gitlab, but so far I only have used this for my classes at Notre Dame that submit assignments through private gitlab repos. A list of my projects in reverse chronological order is below.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>