<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>danewilliams.me</title>
    <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on danewilliams.me</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:52:09 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.danewilliams.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial Post</title>
      <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/initial-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:52:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danewilliams.me/posts/initial-post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog! I plan to use this site to share my projects and code with the world, and may occasionally speak to other interests of mine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danewilliams.me/about/</guid>
      <description>I am an undergraduate computer science student at the University of Notre Dame graduating in 2022. Outside of my studies I spend much of my time at the pool playing for the Notre Dame men&amp;rsquo;s water polo team. Originally, I am from the Bellevue/Eastside area of Seattle, where I attended Eastside Catholic School and graduated in 2018. I am also a proud alumni of the Bellevue Club Swim Team, where I swam for Klaas, Andrew, Dwight, Lee, and Ash since 9 years old until I graduated high school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Me</title>
      <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danewilliams.me/contact/</guid>
      <description>Get In Touch Feel free to get in touch with me!
Email: dane_williams@outlook.com
I am happy to talk about projects or anything for that matter. Please note that the email I have provided is my personal email which I don&amp;rsquo;t always check regularly. Normally, I respond to emails within a couple of days, but it&amp;rsquo;s always possible that you catch me during midterms week and I am a bit slower.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.danewilliams.me/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danewilliams.me/projects/</guid>
      <description>What I&amp;rsquo;ve Been Working On I will try to update this page as I complete new projects, however the most up to date location of all my projects is of course my github. I also have a gitlab, but so far I only have used this for my classes at Notre Dame that submit assignments through private gitlab repos. A list of my projects in reverse chronological order is below.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>